

# **AJESH NAIR**

- Ahmedabad, India, 382481
- +91 9227888821
- 5thaugust@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

# Operations Head | Supply Chain Manager | Fulfillment Head | Warehouse Operations | Logistics Operations | Last Mile

**19 years of experience** in strategic approach towards business excellence. I believe my experience will set benchmark and deliver better result on business case with team work.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Fulfillment Lead, 01/2019 - Current

Areli Commerce Pvt Limited, Ahmedabad, India

- Managing 100 crores GMV orders fulfilment per year, with exponential growth year on year.
- Plan grocery distribution for efficiency in both operations and business development.
- Create and lead a high-performing and motivated team.
- Manage Day to Day Fulfillment Operations and Last mile deliveries across geographies in Gujarat & Udaipur, ensuring fill rates and TAT defined.
- Manage Information from origin to each touch point.
- Implement the necessary standard operating procedures, process, policies, and operational guidelines.
- Maintain MIS and Dashboards on all business parameters and indices. Managing metrics and cost optimization.
- Handling f&v project and coordinating with FnV distributors for entire supply chain operations.
- With more than 3600+ sku's specially in Groceries, beauty, kitchen appliances, personal care, etc.
- Implementation of Inventory & Storage Norms, Material Handling & Storage Practices, Food Safety & other business requirements.
- Industry Leading Cost Structures on Primary & Secondary Transportation and Warehousing.
- Optimizing operations cost of Ahmedabad Fulfilment Centre.
- Over all last mile delivery management, plot routes, and process shipments.
- Evaluate budget and expenditures and ensure all operations guidelines.
- Analyzed strategic, core and support processes, recommending improvements to streamline or automate procedures.
- Developed strategies to maintain required stock levels at minimum cost.
- Created and managed budgets for improved cost control.
- Controlled expenditures by championing efficient use of resources.
- Implemented product storage and flow strategies for minimal delays in fulfilling demand.
- Maintained required inventory levels at minimal cost.
- Formulated operational and administrative procedures to streamline processes.
- Met supply requirements by strengthening inventory systems.

- Implemented new technologies, enhancing operations and increasing production efficiency & evaluate WMS system.
- Tracked inventory levels and optimized ordering strategies to meet availability needs whilst maintaining budget goals.

#### **MANAGER - OPERATIONS**, 12/2016 - 08/2018

**AKP Pvt Ltd**, Ahmedabad, India

## Managed 100% customer excellence on a monthly basis with zero pendency in service complaints.

- Over all operations responsibilities includes, monitoring assigned technicians towards work, Monitoring team work of customer services to make sure we meet promise of our valued customers, Monitoring stores team for supply of material on time.
- Performance as per 5S among the team for daily activity and work flow.
- Analysis problem of corporate and government contracts in case of emergency situations.
- Execution Project of Tender business for Air Conditioner Services for Government Sector across West India.
- Inventory Management of Spares and coordinating with Vendor for supply.
- Monitoring entire transaction from Purchase order to last mile delivery scope of business case.
- Performance Indicator Inventory Management, Work flow management, Close observation of operational activities.
- Developed training program to boost staff capabilities.
- Managed smooth operations and communicated timely updates to coordinate administrative activities.
- Evaluated staffing gaps in skills and performance revenue, facilitating strategic decision-making.
- Tracked expenses in inhouse software and implemented cost controls to eliminate overages.
- Monitored staff performance and developed improvement plans.
- Collaborated with line managers on department performance and KPIs.
- Created facilities management procedures in line with wider business strategy.
- Assessed department operations to prevent future risks and strengthen performance.

SENIOR MANAGER - OPERATIONS, 08/2010 - 12/2016

**Infibeam Incorporation Limited**, Ahmedabad, India

#### Executed 100 crores B2B project in three months of consumer durable product distribution Pan India.

- Conversant with supply planning, logistics management.
- Worked cross-functionally with marketing, sales and finance departments to facilitate daily operations.
- Developed ambitious goals for operational and strategic functions.
- Evaluated reports from front-line managers to make key decisions.
- Resolved problems proactively and decisively, applying business acumen and sound judgment.
- Warehouse with more than 100000+ sku majorly electronics, apparels, computer accessories, etc
- Operations right from procurement of material to last mile delivery.
- Focus on Customer Service, Vendor Management, YOY growth by reducing operational cost
- Worked on projects for INTAS, AMUL, RELIANCE Etc.,
- Managing team of Outbound Logistics, Inbound Logistics, Warehousing
- Performance Indicator Inventory Management, Inbound and outbound logistics

management, Warehouse productivity (cleanliness, employee relations, training, zero occurrence of theft).

#### SENIOR SALES TERRITORY EXECUTIVE, 08/2009 - 07/2010

FedEx India Pvt Ltd, Ahmedabad, India

#### Increased growth month on month and generated new customer 20 lakhs sales in the territory.

- Client Relations and negotiations of Inside and outside sales.
- Conversion of qualified leads into customers and penetrates existing accounts.
- Performance Indicator To increase territory business volume quarterly, Enhance customer satisfaction level as POC for all operational concerns.
- Enhanced working relationships by participating in team-building activities.
- Planned and executed new strategies to increase sales.
- Resolved customer queries and problems using effective communication and providing step-by-step solutions.
- Demonstrated consistent hard work and dedication to achieve results and improve operations.

#### **CHANNEL PARTNER - FOFO**, 05/2006 - 06/2009

**DTDC Courier & Cargo Limited**, Ahmedabad, India

#### Provided best services to the client & build potential customer base.

- Franchisee Management)
- Build own customer base like IIMA, ICRI, ATIRA, etc.
- Handling independently branch for profitability and business growth.
- Performance Indicator To increase business volume quarterly, Enhance customer satisfaction level as POC for all operational concerns.
- Planned and executed new strategies to increase sales.
- Actively listened to customers to fully understand requests and address concerns.

#### **MARKETING EXECUTIVE**, 03/2004 - 04/2006

#### Fedders Lolyd Corporation Ltd, Ahmedabad, India

#### Increase business volume 20% quarterly.

- Meeting all PSU and government sectors for all-inclusive contracts.
- Continuous meeting with all government bodies for smooth operations and services.
- Generating sales volume and business growth quarterly.
- Accountable for business growth.
- Prepared detailed marketing forecasts on daily, weekly and quarterly basis.
- Created sales strategies to promote advertising offerings and motivate larger deals.
- Managed escalated client enquiries with exceptional professionalism and enthusiasm.

#### CUSTOMER SERVICE EXECUTIVE, 08/2003 - 02/2004

Vodafone Ltd, Ahmedabad, India

## Best customer experience by proving customer excellence by providing solution on call.

- Online point of contact for customers for all query.
- Inbound calls.
- Performance Indicator Soft skills, productivity, up-selling skills of VAS.
- Managed all complex complaints, issues and problems to maintain customer
- Added value to customer purchases by upselling additional products and services.

| EDUCATION        | 2003 Bachelors of Commerce                               |
|------------------|--|
| CORE INFORMATION | • 9.1 years of experience within management environment. |
| CERTIFICATIONS   |  |

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Lean Six Sigma Yellow & Green Belt.